I'll just tell you how it ended up.
結果から言えば
I wasn't able to remove
怪異 囲い火蜂の毒を全て僕に移すことはできなかった
all the wreathe-fire bee's poison.
Stay with Karen,
and don't cause
any trouble today.
Koyomi
Stay with Karen,
and don't cause
any trouble today.
Koyomi
ただそれでも火憐の体から 熱はある程度引いた
But even so, Karen's fever went down a little.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Hey, Hachikuji.
よ 八九寺
あ あの...八九寺
U-Um...
Hachikuji?
はあ 阿良々木さんですか
Is that you, Araragi-san?
Come on, screw up my name!
いや 名前噛めよ
Araragi-san, if you're greeting me like a normal person,
阿良々木さん 普通に声をかけてくるなんて
随分とつまらない人間に成り下がりましたね
that means you've gotten boring.
Did something happen?
何かあったのですか
That's pretty harsh!
随分と辛辣だな
Hey, you didn't like it anyway!
そもそもお前だって嫌がってただろうが
I was just acting, so you'd do it more.
あれはもっとしろという振りでしょう
やめろって言われて本当にやめてどうするんですか
You didn't really think "no" meant "no" did you?
Jeez.
Don't
Push
Danger
まったくもう 私のナイスパスが台無しです
You ruined the opportunity I gave you!
お前の振り厳しいよ
Your "acting" is harsh!
You screwed it up right from the start.
出落ちでつまらない
みたいなギャグを見せられてしまった気分です
Now the whole joke's wasted.
そこまで言うか
Was it really that bad?
Hey, Hachikuji.
おい 八九寺 待てよ
Wait...
知りません 私の仲良しだった阿良々木さんは死んでしまいました
I don't know you.
My friend Araragi-san is dead.
阿良々木さんからセクハラ行為を抜いてしまったら
Remove the sexual harassment from Araragi-san,
and there's nothing left but a flea.
ミジンコくらいしか残りませんよ
Flea
Sexual
Harassment
No part of me was a flea to begin with!
ミジンコなんて最初から僕を構成する要素に含まれてねえよ
Flea
I don't even want to see your face.
もう顔も見たくありません 消えてください
Disappear.
Don't say that!
やめて 戦場ヶ原から百回は言われてる台詞だけど
Senjougahara's said that to me a hundred times,
お前に言われると本当に消えてしまいたくなるからやめて
but when you say it, I really want to disappear.
So don't say that...
Huh?
あれ 消えてって言ったのに何でまだいるんですか
I told you to disappear. Why are you still here?
You can't even manage that?
阿良々木さんは消えることもできないんですか
DANGER
AHEAD !
I want to restart from a save point!
セーブポイントからやり直してええええ
で 何があったんですか
So, what happened?
今日は昨日と違って 随分と真剣モードみたいですけれど
You seem pretty serious compared to yesterday.
真剣モード まあそうかもな
Serious, huh?
Yeah, maybe.
A lot of stuff's happened.
色々あったんだよ
はあ まあ 深くは訊きませんが
Well, I won't ask for details.
But Araragi-san,
しかし阿良々木さん 顔色があまり優れないのは気になりますね
you're looking disturbingly pale...
ん そうか
Am I?
少し体調が悪そうです
You don't seem well.
I took half of Karen's illness,
but that shouldn't result in any physical effects.
Wait a minute,
maybe Hachikuji can tell?
囲い火蜂っつーんだってよ
It's something called a wreathe-fire bee.
まあ属性としちゃ お前の蝸牛とは全然違う奴だと思うけれど
It's a totally different type
than your snail, I think.
ただ 面倒な相手ではある
But it's still a problem.
I see.
そうですか 困りましたね
That is a problem...
But I'm sure you'll be fine, Araragi-san.
でもまあきっと 阿良々木さんなら大丈夫ですよ
You always have been, right?
今までだって 阿良々木さんはずっとそうやってきたじゃないですか
だったらいいんだけどな
I hope so...
A lot of stuff is going wrong.
色々 うまくいかなくて参ってるよ
For one thing, my sisters are idiots.
妹達が馬鹿でさ
More idiotic than you?
阿良々木さんよりもですか
僕が馬鹿だっていう前提で話すな
Don't call me an idiot!
言ってることは正しいし それについては尊重したいとも思うんだが
What they're saying is right,
and I'd like to respect that...
But they're too reckless.
どうにも短絡的過ぎる
They want to serve justice, but they aren't doing it right.
やりたいことは正しいのに やり方が分かってない
That's how it feels.
そんな風に見える
Isn't that what you're always being told?
それは 阿良々木さんがいつも言われていることでは
それに 阿良々木さんがそういう人じゃなかったら
And if you weren't like that,
私もこんなところで暢気にお散歩なんかできていませんし
I wouldn't be able to take a nice walk around here.
でしたら その妹さん達に救われている人も
So doesn't that mean that
they've saved a lot of people?
いっぱいいるということではありませんか
だけど なんかあいつらはガキだって言うか
Still, they're just kids.
人の話なんか全然聞かないんだもん
They don't listen to a word anyone says.
I have to do this
今回のことだって あいつらが大人しくしているうちにケリをつけなきゃ
while they're still sensible enough to stay home.
大人しく...か
Sensible...
Hachikuji, when do you think you become an adult?
八九寺 人はいつ大人になるんだろうな
そういうことを言っているうちはなれませんね
Not when you're still saying things like that.
In Japan, you officially become an adult at twenty,
成人が二十歳と言っても そんなの時代によって違いますしね
but it changes, depending on the era.
働き始めたら大人と言う考え方もありますが
Some people consider you an adult once you're working.
働かなくとも別に大人にもなれますからね
But you can be an adult without a job.
歳を取れば誰でも大人になれるって奴か
You can become an adult just by aging, huh?
まあ確かに 中学三年と中学二年の奴に
I guess telling two girls in their second and third year
大人になれっつってもそりゃ無理な話か
of middle school to grow up is asking too much.
Age-wise, they're kids.
実年齢的にガキなんだから
そこでしょう
That's the point!
中学生が子供なのは当たり前ですけれど
It's natural for a middle schooler to be a kid.
But the fact that
自分が子供だと分かっていないところが問題なのです
they don't realize they're kids is the problem.
They may still be better than adults
それでも 自分を大人だと思っていない大人よりはマシかもしれませんが
who don't think they're adults.
自分を子供だと思ってる大人ほど手の付けられないもんもねーだろうけどな
There's nothing more difficult to deal with
than an adult who thinks they're a kid...
ちなみに八九寺 お前は自分のことを何だと思ってるんだ
By the way, Hachikuji, how do you think of yourself?
The body of a child and the brains of an adult.
体は子供 頭脳は大人です
So you're a detective?
名探偵かよ
で 八八寺 なんの話だっけ
Then, Hachihachiji...
What were we talking about?
Araragi-san, you're missing a temple.
阿良々木さん 寺が一個減っています
I see.
ああそうか 気がつかなかった
I didn't realize. Sorry.
悪い 八七寺
Hachishichiji.
We're losing temples every time you say my name?
私の名を呼ぶごとに寺が一つずつ減っていくシステムなのですか
八六寺 もう戦場ヶ原の家につきそうだから
Hachirokuji.
We're almost at Senjougahara's house.
この辺でお別れしないと
We should split up here.
え ああ そうですね そうでした
Oh, right.
You're right.
あのかたは私のことが嫌いなのでした
She doesn't like me.
では阿良々木さん お元気で
Farewell, Araragi-san.
Stay well.
You too.
お前こそな
しかし この時僕は知らなかったのだ
But at the time, I didn't know
what would happen to the cheerful young girl
この先 八九寺真宵と言う名前の
あの気立てのいい少女の身に
named Hachikuji Mayoi.
一体何が起こるのかを...
Just kidding.
なんて
Honestly, I have no idea what will happen.
いや マジで知らないだけなんだけど
Now, then. What should I do?
Where should I go?
Karen didn't leave a hint of where she'd gone, so I have no way to look. I'd just search randomly.
This has become even more bothersome now that she's disappeared.
Unlike Senjougahara, Karen should have no way of contacting Kaiki.
And even if she did, Kaiki wouldn't just meet with her again so easily.
I'm glad I lent Hanekawa my bicycle.
If I hadn't, Karen would've taken it without asking.
Her range of whereabouts would be much larger if she were on a bicycle.
No, she could have just as easily taken a bus.
I don't have a season pass, but my sisters do.
Think.
What would I do in Karen's place?
She's not in her best condition, but she still feels as though she has to do something.
Even though others tried to stop her, she just won't stop...
Gah! I just don't know. How could I even understand such a idiot?
Karen Bee Part 6
Episode 6
Type Font Used HGP Minchou B
Tamikurasou
C
.
Be careful with fire
Um...
C
Be careful with fire
.
ええと ガハラさん
Gahara-san?
A question, Araragi-kun...
ねえ 阿良々木くん
たまたま持ち歩いていた百本の尖った鉛筆が
If, by some strange coincidence, a hundred sharp pencils
I was carrying embedded themselves into a third party,
何かの弾みで第三者に刺さってしまったとしても
それは事故と言うものよね
would that be judged as an accidental death?
No, it would be murder!
Caution: Entry is Prohibited
いや 事件だ 大事件だ
First-degree murder!
鉛筆で人を殺した事件が三面トップを飾る
The next day's headlines would read, "Man Killed by Pencils!"
ふふ ならば私はその新聞の上で再び鉛筆を削るわ
Then I'd sharpen more pencils on top of those headlines.
Calm down, Senjougahara!
落ち着け戦場ヶ原
You may think that's a good line, but it really isn't!
してやったりみたいな顔をしても
そんなにうまいこと言えてないぞ
C
SENJOUGAHARA
Take off your shoes and come in, Araragi-kun.
とりあえず靴を脱いであがりなさいな 阿良々木くん
心配しなくとも もう監禁したりしないから
Don't worry.  I won't tie you up again.
お邪魔します
Thanks...
Well?
で お前がそうまで武装準備をしている理由は
C
If I ask, will you tell me why you're
訊いたら教えてもらえるもんなのか
arming yourself so heavily?
I'm going to go and chat with Kaiki.
貝木と話をつけに行くのよ
阿良々木くんが私の保護を拒否する以上
As you've refused my protection,
I've no choice but to go on the attack.
私は攻撃に打って出るしかないわ
拉致監禁を保護と言い換えるな
C
Be careful with fire
One match can start a fire
.
Kidnapping and protection are not the same thing!
C
Be careful with fire
One match can start a fire
C
Be careful with fire
One match can start a fire
C
Be careful with fire
By the way, I talked to Hanekawa afterwards.
そう言えば あの後羽川と話したんだが
What?
え 羽川さま あ...いや
Did Hanekawa-sama...
I mean, did Hanekawa-san say anything about me?
羽川さんが私のこと何か言ってたの
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
Did you just say "Hanekawa-sama"?
お前今 羽川さまって言ったか
I-I did not.
い...言ってないわ 我が校にいじめはありません
Bullying Is A Crime
There is no bullying occurring at my school.
You're being bullied? You?
C
SENJOUGAHARA
いじめられてんの お前が
I mean, given the way you act,
そりゃお前が素で行動してれば羽川からは色々注意されることはあるだろうが
I can see you might attract a lot of Hanekawa's attention.
いじめられてるとか言うなよ 人聞きの悪い
But don't say you're being bullied...
That's mean.
だから 別にそんなこと言ってないじゃない
I'm not saying that.
I'm polishing her shoes every morning
毎朝羽川さんの靴を磨いているのも
私が好きでやらさせていただいていることよ
because I enjoy doing so.
何で羽川に対してそこまで卑屈なんだ
Why do you act like that toward her?
Anyway,
ともかく 貝木に会いに行くってこったな
you're going to see Kaiki, right?
C
でも戦場ヶ原 お前貝木の居場所分かるのか
But, Senjougahara, do you know where he is?
I have a business card from long ago,
名刺があったのよ
昔 あの男から受け取った名刺
that he gave me.
It's a miracle I never threw it away.
今まで破り捨てずにいたのは奇跡ね
ふうん
Ghost Buster
Kaiki         Deishuu
戦場ヶ原 今から僕世界一酷いことを言うけど
Senjougahara, I'm about to say
the worst thing in the world.
Ghost Buster
Kaiki          Deishuu
But if you fell for this, isn't it partially your own fault?
お前これ 騙される方も悪くないか
That's the trap.
そういう罠なのよ
You'd never think that anyone who'd give themselves
まさかそんな間の抜けた肩書きを名乗る奴が
such a ridiculous title would actually be a con man.
本当に詐欺師だとは思わないじゃない
そんなもんかな
Is that how it works?
So what, Senjougahara?
ってことは戦場ヶ原 お前あれか
You called this number and spoke with him?
この番号に電話して 貝木と話したのか
Kai
Yes.
ええ あの男まるで変ってなかったわね
He hadn't changed a bit.
辛気臭いったらないわ
As gloomy as ever.
Can I go with you?
僕もついていっていいか
Kai
If you're going to speak with Kaiki, I want to go...
貝木と話をつけるなら 僕も一緒に
I can still pretend I didn't hear that.
今なら聞かなかったことにしてあげてもいいわよ
死にたくなければ 前言撤回なさい
Unless you wish to die, take that back.
My sister was one of his victims.
妹がな 貝木の被害に遭ったんだよ
Ghost Buster
Kaiki        Deishuu
囲い火蜂とかいう わけのわからん怪異を無理矢理に押し付けられて
He set some bizarre monster
called a wreathe-fire bee on her.
高熱に魘されている
She's suffering from a terrible fever.
I've taken half of it upon myself to neutralize it,
今は僕がその怪異を半分ほど引き受ける形で何とか中和してるけれど
but I don't know what could happen in the future.
それだってこの先 どう転ぶか不明だ
阿良々木くんが半分引き受けた
You took half of it yourself?
そんなことをして 阿良々木くんは大丈夫なの
Will you be okay?
吸血鬼の治癒スキルがあるから 大丈夫ではある
My vampiric healing ability is keeping me safe.
さすがに万全とは言いがたいけれど
It isn't perfect, but...
I see.
そう つまりもう後には退けないというわけね
Then there's no turning back for you.
そもそも妹さんが絡んでるんじゃ
But I suppose with your sister involved,
that was never really a possibility.
阿良々木くんが退くわけがないか
C
.
Be careful with fire
One match can start a fire
That's not all.
それだけじゃない
You're involved too.
お前も絡んでる
C
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
.
Your trying to deal with Kaiki alone, for my sake, is insane.
僕のために お前が貝木と一人で対決しようなんて馬鹿げてる
Am I wrong?
違うか
It isn't only for your sake.
別に阿良々木くんのためだけと言うわけじゃないわ
This matter with Kaiki is
something I need to settle for myself.
貝木のことは 私がつけなければならない決着の一つなのよ
To the point where, had he not returned,
もしも貝木がこの町に戻ってこなければ
I'd have gone looking for him.
こちらから先に探しに行ったほどの
Why are you so obsessed?
何でそこまで
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
Wasn't it a little thing?
些細なこと...じゃなかったのかよ
That was me tsundere-ing.
あれはツンデレったのよ
Tsundere-ing?
C
ツンデレったって
Do you plan to seek revenge on all five con artists?
お前 そんな風に五人の詐欺師の全員に復讐でもする気か
It's over.
もう終わったことだろう
お前がつけなければならない決着は 他にあるんじゃないのか
Aren't there other things you need to settle?
Of course not.
まさか 五人の詐欺師と言ってもね
Like Oshino-san told me, I won't pretend
忍野さんの言葉じゃないけれど
to be the helpless victim of those con artists.
私は被害者面をするつもりはないの
I relied on them, and I was betrayed.
こちらから頼って裏切られたんだから
My personality isn't such that I still...
それで逆恨みしようってほど
私の人格は...私の人格は
My personality...
C
My personality isn't the issue here.
私の人格はともかくとして 筋を外すつもりはないわ
I won't do that.
C
One match can start a fire
お前の人格は問題ありなんだな
You have some personality problems, don't you?
だけど 貝木だけは別
But Kaiki is a different matter.
Why?
どうして
He's the one responsible for my mom and dad's divorce.
お父さんとお母さんの離婚を促したのが 貝木だからよ
Naturally, I can't blame the entire thing on Kaiki,
勿論 すべてを貝木のせいにはできないし
するつもりもないけれど
and I don't intend to.
But he ruined my family.
あの男は私たち家族を弄んだ
I can't forgive that.
それは許せないことなの
If I forgave it...
それを許してしまうと
I would no longer be myself.
私は私でなくなる
Even without Kaiki,
貝木がいなくとも お父さんとお母さんはきっと離婚したと思う
my mom and dad would probably have divorced.
I think my family would have been split up.
私の家族はばらばらになっていたと思う
It's likely my fault that Mom left...
お母さんがいなくなったのは 私のせいだとも思う
But, Araragi-kun,
でもね 阿良々木君
does the fact that the result would have
だからって 悪意をもってそうされたことを
been the same forgive the fact he caused it?
どうせ結果は同じだからと 許せると思う
Does the fact that it would have happened
悪意をもってそうされたことを
sooner or later, forgive the fact he made it happen, out of malice?
どうせ早いか遅いかの違いだからと 許せると思う
Malice
"Malice."
悪意
Malice is something I have a monopoly on.
悪意は私の専売特許よ
いや それは知らないけど
I don't know about that.
Ghost Buster
Kaiki             Deishuu
Kaiki used the crab I met to ruin
Ghost Buster
Kaiki             Deishuu
貝木は金欲しさに 私の出遭った蟹を理由に
Ghost Buster
Kaiki             Deishuu
my family, all for money.
私の家庭を滅茶苦茶にした
Ghost Buster
Kaiki             Deishuu
It's too late to say this, but it makes no difference now.
いまさら どうせ同じことだろうと
C
It's possible that you were a secondary concern for me,
阿良々木君のことなんて 私にとっては本当は二の次だったのかもね
and that protecting you was simply an excuse.
阿良々木君を守るなんてのは体のいい口実で
In the end, I simply hate Kaiki.
私は結局 貝木を憎んでいるだけなのかも
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
An excuse?
口実って
So I tsundere-ed.
だからツンデレったのよ
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いしないでよね
I'm not doing this for your sake, Araragi-kun.
別に阿良々木君のためにやってるんじゃないのだから よ
そんなことは
That is
probably not true.
多分 ないさ
The crab...
蟹 戦場ヶ原の出遭った蟹
CRAB
The crab that Senjougahara met.
STOP
Beast
Perversion and Sexual Desire
PRAYING
Flashback
その蟹に憑かれていた最中の出来事
This occurred while the crab was possessing her.
In Surgery
Devil's right hand
God's left hand
Torso
Head
CRAB
ならば きっと戦場ヶ原は
She couldn't even hate Kaiki Deishuu when it happened.
CRAB
その際には貝木泥舟を憎むことさえできなかったはずだ
BROKEN
M
a
O
M
That was how the crab worked.
あれはそういう種類の怪異だった
Hand
本来なら 子供のように怒るべきだった
She should have gotten angry like a child.
A child who'd lost her mom.
母を亡くした子供のように
But then there is...
ただそうなると
one thing I don't understand.
ひとつだけ わからないな
貝木ってのは偽物の詐欺師のはずだろう
Kaiki is a con man and a fake, right?
But from what you have said,
it sounds like he saw your crab.
それなのに その話じゃ
お前の蟹に気付いていた風にも聞こえるけれど
I don't know.
さてね
でも 本物以上の力を持つ偽物なんて
But a fake with more power than the real thing
is more dangerous than the real thing.
本物以上に厄介よ
C
Of course, at the time
もちろん 当時はただのインチキだと思っただけだけれど
I thought he was just another sleazy con artist.
でも それも今思えば
But thinking back,
あえて無能を装っていただけかも
he may have deliberately feigned incompetence
to draw more money from my father.
お父さんから より多くのお金を引き出すために
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
He's spending his time taking pocket change from middle schoolers now.
今は中学生相手の小遣い稼ぎに勤しんでいるらしいぜ
And he hurt my sister when she tried to stop him.
それを防ごうとして うちの妹はやられたんだ
そう 阿良々木君の妹も正義マンなのね
I see.
Your sister is an ally of justice like you.
Stop calling me that!
だから 正義マンって
栂の木二中のファイヤーシスターズ
The Fire Sisters of Tsuganoki 2nd Middle School.
I'd heard the rumors.
まあ 噂は聞いていたんだけれど
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
Come to think of it, you did hear about them.
そういや 知ってんだったな
Just so we're clear, Araragi-kun,
言っておくけれど 阿良々木君
my impression is that
私の印象では 貝木の不吉に正義は通用しないわよ
"right" is a concept that won't work on him.
And "right" is all you have,
はっきり言うけれど
阿良々木君は正義だけあって
which makes you strong against hypocrites
偽善には強くとも悪人には弱い
but weak against someone who's truly evil.
C
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
.
I told you I'm not like that...
だから 正義じゃねえって
However,
でも お前が犯罪者になるのを見過ごせるか
I won't sit back and let you become a criminal.
罪を犯すつもりはないわ
I've no intention of committing any crimes.
罰を与えるだけよ
I'm just going to punish him...
In modern society the two are identical.
fire
現代社会においてそれは同じことだ
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
Senjougahara, you might not know this,
戦場ヶ原 お前は知らないのかもしれないけどさ
but I love you.
僕はお前を愛してるんだよ
Even if you become a criminal and end up in jail,
たとえお前が犯罪者になって刑務所に収容されても
I'll still visit you every day.
毎日面会に行くくらい
But I'd rather be with you all the time.
だけど どうせならいつでも一緒にいたい
うっかりすると
Sometimes I don't know why I'm dating you.
どうしてお前と付き合っているのかわからなくなってしまうけれど
C
.
One match can start a fire
Be careful with fire
But I love you so much, I don't need a reason.
理由なんか必要ないくらい お前が好きだ
If you're going, then let's go together.
行くなら一緒に行こう
お前は僕を守ってくれ 僕はお前を守ってやる
You can protect me...
I'll protect you.
Oh, no.
やぱ過ぎ 超絶かっこいい
So incredibly cool...
If I were a man,
私が男だったら そのあまりの男っぷりに対して
I'd be so jealous of your manliness that I'd kill you.
嫉妬に狂って殺してるわ
Terrifying!
恐怖
TERRIFYING
I'm glad I'm a woman
女でよかった あなたを好きでいられる
because I can love you...
C
I understand, Araragi-kun.
阿良々木君 わかりました
I'll do as you say.
あなたの言うとおりにしましょう
Then you'll take me to Kaiki?
じゃあ 貝木のところに 一緒に連れて行ってくれるのか
Yes.
ええ ただしその代わり ひとつだけお願いがあるわ
But in exchange, I do have a request.
お願い
A request?
If you dislike the presumption
implied by the word "request,"
お願いという甘えた言い方が嫌いなら
条件でもいいけどね
then call it a condition.
A condition required before I'll take you to Kaiki.
阿良々木君を貝木に引き合わせるための条件
What will you do?
どうする
I'll do it.
聞くさ それがどんな願いでも
I'll do it gladly, no matter what it is or how many there are.
いくつでも引き受ける
I have just one request, Araragi-kun.
私のお願いはひとつだけよ
阿良々木君
今回 これから貝木と会うことで
By meeting with Kaiki, I intend to resolve things with myself.
私はけじめをつけるつもり
Just like my master cut...
ご主人さま
いえ  羽川さんが髪を切ったようにね
I mean, Hanekawa-san cut her hair.
That is a remarkable mistake to make.
気になるどころの言い間違いじゃねえ
M
Y
MA
とてもじゃねえが聞き流せねえ
And not something I can pretend I didn't hear!
ST
ER
I am not being threatened.
脅されてないわよ
You're being threatened? By Hanekawa?
脅されてるの 羽川に
No matter where I am,
そこがどこであろうと
羽川さんの前では正座するのが当然でしょう
it's natural that I should kneel before Hanekawa-san.
C
USE
BUTTONS
AT
NIGHT
No matter where you are?
どこであろうとですか
Just as Hanekawa-san...
羽川さんが 羽川さんが髪を切ったように
As Hanekawa-san cut her hair.
そうやってあの子が 前に進んだように
Just as doing that let her move forward,
by confronting Kaiki, I can finally leave my past behind.
私は貝木と対決することで
自分の過去と決別するつもり
I'm going to move forward.
私も 前に進むわ
C
で だからお願いってなんなんだよ
So, what's your request?
What must I do for you to take me with you?
どうすれば 僕を一緒に連れて行ってくれるんだ
I can't say yet.
今はまだ言えないわね
It's something you can't tell me?
言えないようなことなのかよ
C
SENJOUGAHARA
貝木との対決を終えてから その結果がどうであれ
Once things are settled with Kaiki,
no matter what the outcome,
I'll tell you then.
そのときに言うことにするわ
Then there's no difference if you say it now.
だったら今言ってもおんなじだろ
If I said it now, it wouldn't be foreshadowing.
今言ったら伏線にならないじゃない
伏線なのかよ
It's foreshadowing?!
C
That's right.
After you die,
そう 阿良々木君の死後
私はそのお願いをこの場面で口にしなかったことを後悔しながら
I'll have to spend the rest of my life alone,
regretting that I didn't say anything now.
ひとりで生きていくの
It's foreshadowing my death?
僕が死ぬような伏線なのか
That's right.
そう そしてクライマックスシーンでは重要なアイテムとして
And at the climax,
the telescope you gave me
誕生日に阿良々木君からもらった天体望遠鏡が使われるのよ
for my birthday will be featured as an important item.
There isn't any scene involving a telescope!
天体望遠鏡が使われるようなイベントなんかねえよ
Just tell me what it is.
いいから今言え 伏線なんか知るか
Screw the foreshadowing!
Then let's forget the whole thing.
そう言うなら この話はなしよ
わかったよ それでいい
Fine... I'll do it.
All right.
そう ならば一緒に行きましょう
Then let's go.
Let's protect each other.
互いを守りあいましょう
I promised I'd meet him at 5:00 PM.
約束の時間は午後五時よ
Right...
C
SENJOUGAHARA
そっか じゃ僕は一旦家に戻るよ
Then I'll be heading home.
Very well.
そう では夕方頃 また来て頂戴
Come back in the early evening, then.
Yeah.
おう くれぐれも勝手に行動するなよ
Don't do anything on your own, okay?
Of course not.
当たり前よ
Have I ever lied?
私がこれまで 一度でも嘘をついたことがあった
Don't worry.
安心なさい
This time, it's to get you to hear my request.
今回は阿良々木君に私のお願いをきいてもらうためだもの
I might lie, but I'll keep my promise.
嘘はつくかもしれないけれど 約束は守るわよ
All right...
C
SENJOUGAHARA
そうか
Well, then that's okay.
まあ それならいいんだけど
ふっ これは取引よ
Yes.
This is a trade.
And...
それに さすがの私もやや眠い
Even I'm starting to get a little tired.
C
SENJOUGAHARA
阿良々木君も
You've been up all night
気を失っていた時間があるとは言え 徹夜でしょう
even if you were unconscious for a while.
Kaiki isn't someone you can deal with on no sleep.
とてもじゃないけれど
貝木は寝ぼけた頭で相手のできる詐欺師ではないわ
まあ 睡眠に関しちゃ 我慢のきくほうなんだけどな
Well, I think I deal with no sleep better than most.
As a former vampire.
元吸血鬼の体質で
But rest up anyway.
でも 寝ておきなさいな
You might not be able to sleep tonight.
今夜 眠れるとは限らないのだから
お兄ちゃん
Onii-chan?
Oh, you're up?
あ 起きたのか おはよ
Good morning.
Karen-chan's missing!
火憐ちゃんがいなくなった
When I got up...
わ 私がさっき起きたら
火憐ちゃん どこにもいなくって
she wasn't there...
And she can't be fully healed yet!
まだ治ってるはずないのに
落ち着け 月火ちゃん
Calm down, Tsukihi-chan!
く 靴もないし 服も着替えたみたいだし
Her shoes are gone,
and it looks like she changed her clothes...
落ち着け 心当たりはないのか
Calm down.
Do you have any idea where she'd go?
Anywhere she'd likely be?
あいつが行きそうな場所の心当たり
None...
ないよ
I think she'd go to that Kaiki guy's place.
貝木って人のところだとは思うけれど
でも そもそもその人の居場所がわからないんだもん
But I don't know where he is...
Does that mean Karen-chan knows?
ってことは 火憐ちゃんは貝木の居場所を知ってるのか
She shouldn't.
知らないはず
一度逃がしてるんだし
She let him go once.
I'll look for her.
僕が探してくる お前は家で待っていろ
You wait here.
え でも 私も探しに
But I want to go too.
お前じゃ火憐ちゃんと会ったとき 逆に説得されてしまう危険がある
If you find her, there's a risk she'll persuade you to go with her.
You really don't trust me, do you?
本当に信用してないんだね
I don't.
信用してない でも 心配はしている
But I do worry.
But more than that, I'm mad!
でも それ以上に怒ってんだよ
Think.
考えろ 僕が火憐だったらどうする
If I were Karen, what would I do?
まず 家から離れようとするだろう
First, she'd want to get away from the house.
C
PARKING
ENTRANCE
CARS
EXITING
C
PARKING
ENTRANCE
CARS
EXITING
C
No Parking Please
見つかったら連れ戻されるんだから
Because if I found her, I'd take her back.
No Parking Please
C
That much is certain.
それは最低条件で そして問題はそれからだ
The problem is, what then?
それから それから それから
What then? What then? What then?
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
うるさいのう
Be quiet...
You're being too loud for me to sleep.
騒がしくて眠れやせんわ
お前様が動揺すれば
When you panic,
that panic is transmitted directly to me.
その動揺はダイレクトにわしに伝わるのじゃ
C
Sasaki Clinic
忍 状況はわかってるか
Shinobu,
do you know what's going on?
概ねの
Basically.
Your sister is almost as reckless as you are...
まったく
お前様に負けず劣らず 無鉄砲な妹御じゃのう
おお そう言えば わしも迷子になったところを
Come to think of it,
お前様に探してもらったことがあったかのう
you once searched for me when I was lost.
懐かしや 懐かしや
How wonderfully nostalgic.
C
FULL
Can I ask if you're going to help me?
協力してくれるかって 聞いていい
Ha ha.
かかっ 残念ながら
Unfortunately,
今のわしはお前様に逆らうことのできん立場でな
I'm not in a position to refuse any request you make.
主従関係は複雑であろうと
The question of which one of us is the master
is a complicated one,
C
FULL
力関係ではお前様のほうが上じゃ
but you're certainly the stronger.
I've told you a bunch of times that
吸血鬼の絆は魂の絆じゃと
the bonds of a vampire are bonds of the soul, right?
散々教えてやったろう
Thus,
ゆえにお前様から命令があれば
for any order you give me,
それがどんな不本意な内容であれ わしは逆らえんの
no matter how much I may want to refuse, I cannot.
C
FULL
NO TRUCKS
It isn't an order.
命令じゃない 僕はお前に命令できる立場にはない
I'm not in a position to order you.
Then I won't do it, idiot.
ならばきけんぞ たわけ
C
Sasaki Clinic
What you just saw
今のは
協力してやるがこちらからそう申し出るのは決まりが悪いので
was me saying I'd help you, but I'd rather not say so.
So please allow me to save face by calling it an order.
体面上命令という言葉を使えという意味じゃと
Why couldn't you tell?
なぜわからん
C
NO TRUCKS
Showing up right now, when I should clearly
このタイミングで眠気をおしてのわしの登場
どう考えてもお前様に協力するために出てきておるじゃろうが
be asleep was obviously so that I could help you.
You're a tsundere too.
お前も立派なツンデレだよ
じゃあ 命令だ
Then it's an order.
Get off your ass and find out
where Karen-chan is already!
火憐ちゃんがどこにいるか 探しやがれ
あーあ嫌じゃ嫌じゃ
Oh, no... Oh, no.
What cruel fate forces me to obey the orders
何が悲しゅうて
こんなどうでもいい下等な人間如きに従わねばならんのやら
of a lesser being like this human?
しかしそんな風に強権を発動されてしまえば仕方ないのう
But I cannot disobey an order...
ふん まったく
You can't do anything without me around.
お前様はわしがおらねば何にもできんようじゃ
You're so cute when you need my help.
いやはや どうしようもなく可愛い奴じゃのう かかっ
Ha ha.
Your sister's blood is structurally similar to yours.
妹御の血はお前様の血と構造的に似たようなものじゃ
ならばわしにはその匂いで おおよその場所はつかむことができる
So I can tell where she is by the smell.
She doesn't seem to have gone very far...
どうやらそこまで離れた場所ではないようじゃの
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Hi, I'm Tsukihi!
We're the fire sisters!
I'm fine on my own!
You can't make an omelet without breaking eggs, they say.
While this saying appears rather profound and deep at first, isn't it shockingly trivial?
I'm worried about them...
The implication seems to be that breaking eggs is necessary for an omelet.
Perfect!
Go help them out!
If that's all it takes for something to be immortalized as a proverb, I can do it too.
What!
You're the assistant
we asked for?
Resume
You won't see the sun unless dawn breaks.
If you don't do your homework, it won't be done.
All right, let's start with patrolling the town.
If you don't go to school, you won't be late.
If I had no brother, I'd be free!
Next time! Karen Bee, Part 7!
Next Time
Karen Bee Part 7
If Karen Bee doesn't end, there'll be no Tsukihi Phoenix!
Oh, no! We're lost!